The human digestive system consists of two major parts: the gastrointestinal — GI — tract and the accessory organs.
يتكون الجهاز الهضمي للإنسان من جزأين رئيسيين: الجهاز الهضمي والأعضاء الملحقة.
The GI tract begins with the oral cavity, which houses the tongue, teeth, and salivary glands.
يبدأ الجهاز الهضمي بالتجويف الفموي، الذي يضم اللسان والأسنان والغدد اللعابية.
The mouth mechanically breaks down food and initiates carbohydrate digestion.
يقوم الفم بتفكيك الطعام ميكانيكيًا ويبدأ هضم الكربوهيدرات.
The pharynx is a muscular tube behind the mouth that helps propel the chewed food to the esophagus.
البلعوم عبارة عن أنبوب عضلي يقع خلف الفم ويساعد في دفع الطعام الممضوغ إلى المريء.
The esophagus transports food to the stomach through rhythmic contractions called peristalsis.
يقوم المريء بنقل الطعام إلى المعدة من خلال انقباضات منتظمة تسمى التمعج.
The stomach is located below the diaphragm.
تقع المعدة أسفل الحجاب الحاجز.
It stores and churns food and aids in the enzymatic breakdown of proteins.
تخزن وتخلط الطعام وتساعد في التحلل الأنزيمي للبروتينات.
The small intestine is a coiled tube in the central and lower abdomen.
الأمعاء الدقيقة عبارة عن أنبوب ملتف في وسط البطن وأسفلها.
It is responsible for nutrient absorption and fat digestion.
إنها مسؤولة عن امتصاص العناصر الغذائية وهضم الدهون.
The large intestine, or colon, follows the small intestine.
الأمعاء الغليظة، أو القولون، تتبع الأمعاء الدقيقة.
It absorbs water, electrolytes, and vitamins and houses beneficial gut bacteria.
يمتص الماء والشوارد والفيتامينات ويحتضن بكتيريا الأمعاء المفيدة.
The anus is the terminal part of the rectum, involved in eliminating waste.
الشرج هو الجزء النهائي من المستقيم، وهو يشارك في التخلص من الفضلات.
The accessory digestive organs include the liver, pancreas, and gallbladder.
تشمل الأعضاء الهضمية الإضافية الكبد والبنكرياس والمرارة.
@